Hugo A. Matilla Gómez

Senior Android Developer

Address: Plaza Penuelas, 28005, Madrid Tel: 0034619037089

e-mail: hugo.matilla@gmail.com

Date of Birth: 27/01/1981 Nationality: Spanish web: matgom.com

OBJECTIVE

I want to be part of the Help Scout engineering team and to contribute with my experience in Android developments, I.T. business and team work. I feel extremely motivated to continue improving my career in Software development. Help Scout, with its focus on customer experience and large engineering team presents a great opportunity. Moreover I could apply my knowledge and motivation to improve Help Scout.

MY PROJECTS

After almost four years working at Scondoo as main Android Developer and more than one year at SMF, I have been involved in many projects that are now in the Android Play Store. The duration of the developments I have worked on varied from 1 month to more than a year, and were undertaken both as solo projects and in teams. I also have formative experience in Windows Phone, iOS and JavaScript. Some of the Android projects that can be found in the store include: scondoo, HotUkDeals, reBuy, LernCoachies and DHL.

EXPERIENCE

EXPERIENCE	
Android Developer scondoo Berlin/Remote. August. 2013 - Present	At scondoo I overtook with agility and speed the code developed by 2 different agencies. This code was in several cases unstructured. Thanks to my experience I improved it with ease, not only in performance but also in design.
9	Technical Skills: Android, Java, Kotlin, JSON, Git, JavaScript
Android Developer HotUKDeals Berlin. Nov. 2014 – Feb.2015	I worked remotedly with the HotUKDeals team in Canada building the new generic app, where I rapidly aquire the knowledge of the software architecture and the team methodologies to help them increase their development process.
	Technical Skills: Android, Java, Clean Architecture
Android Developer Smart Mobile Factory Berlin. May. 2012 – July.2013	My ability to quickly adapt to new concepts has been useful to develop and improve various Android Applications. Obstacles I must regularly overcome include definition changes, new features, improvements and tight deadlines.
	Technical Skills: Android, Java, JSON, XML, Windows Phone, Parse.
Web App & ETL Developer Innova-TSN Madrid. Jan. 2011 - Feb. 2012	I was quickly integrated in different projects, while experiencing new technical tools, supplying ideas and helping to find solutions. Additionally I assumed managerial and technical responsibilities, and regularly shared my expertise in Oracle with my colleagues.
	Technical Skills: Java, JSP, Html, Css, Batch, C#, Oracle, Eclipse.
ETL Developer AlamoConsulting	I was part of a small team that developed a large scale corporate DataWarehouse, where versatility was a constant challenge.
Madrid. Jul. 2009 - Dec. 2010	Technical Skills: Oracle, SAS, SAS DIS

EDUCATION

Postgraduate Studies Mobile Development and Services

Universidad Nacional de Educación a Distancia

Madrid. Dec. 2010 - Jul. 2011

Main Subject Areas: Mobile Web and Android Applications development.

Minor Subject Areas: Mobile technologies, history, monetization, and IOS development.

Technical Skills: HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, Java, Android, Objective-C, IOS.

Main Subject Areas: Programming Methodologies, Software Engineering, Computer Networks, Operating Systems, Databases, Computer Architectures,

Minor Subject Areas: Digital Systems, Microcontrollers

Programming.

Thesis: Fairness and Market Based Techniques in Wireless Sensor Networks. Grade 1.3 (TU-Berlin).

Computer Science Engineering MSc.

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid Madrid. Sep. 1999 - Mar. 2009

LANGUAGES

English	TOEFL Score 94. December 2010.
German	B2 Private School.
Spanish	Mother Tongue.

I.T. SKILLS

Languages	Fluent: JAVA, Kotlin, JavaScript. Basic: Swift, Python, Haskell
WEB	Fluent: HTML5, CSS3, Nodejs. Basic: React, Meteor, Polymer, WorPress, Jekyll.
Databases	Fluent: SQLite, MongoDB, Oracle. Basic: Realm, MySQL.
Operating Systems	Fluent: OSX, Windows, Android. Basic: UNIX, iOS.
Documentation	Fluent: UML, E-R. Basic: Gantt.
Agile	Fluent: Kanban, Scrum
Version Control Systems	Fluent: Git

FURTHER INFORMATION

- Erasmus Programme: TU-Berlin 2007-2009
- Tae-Kwon-Do and Muay Thay black belt.
- Mentor at CoderDojo
- More at <u>matgom.com/about</u>